Inventory of the United States Army, Third Army miscellaneous records
Hoover Institution Archives
United States Army, Third Army miscellaneous records
1918-1919
XX296
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Reports, including an official history of the United States Third Army in France and Germany, 1918 November to 1919 July; and summaries of Third Army intelligence reports, 1918 November to 1919 June.
United States. Army. Army, 3rd.
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
This collection is comprised of reports, including an official history of the United States Third Army in France and Germany, 1918 November to 1919 July; and summaries of Third Army intelligence reports, 1918 November to 1919 June. It also contains maps, photographs, and memorabilia pertaining to the Rhine River Valley.
United States. Army. American Expeditionary Forces.; Germany--History--Allied occupation, 1918-1930.; World War, 1914-1918--Campaigns--Western Front.
- History of the Third U.S. Army, November 14, 1918 to July 2, 1919 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Headquarters Third U.S. Army. Second Section. Summaries of Intelligence
  - Numbers 1-20, 1918 November 17-December 5 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - 21-30, 1918 December 7-December 16 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - 31-40, 1918 December 17-December 26 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - 41-50, 1918 December 27-1919 January 5 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - 51-60, 1919 January 6-January15 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - 61-70, 1919 January 16-January 25 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - 71-80, 1919 January 25-February 4 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - 81-90, 1919 February 5-February14 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - 91-100, 1919 February 15-February 24 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - 101-110, 1919 February 25-March 6 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - 111-120, 1919 March 7-March 16 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - 121-130, 1919 March 17-March 26 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - 131-140, 1919 March 27-April 5 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - 141-150, 1919 April 6-April 15 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - 151-160, 1919 April 16-April 25 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - 161-170, 1919 April 26-May 5 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - 170-180, 1919 May 5-May 15 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - 181-190, 1919 May 16-May 25 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - 191-200, 1919 May 26-June 4 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - 201-210, 1919 June 5-June 14 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - 211-220, 1919 June 15-June 24 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - 221-224, 1919 June 24-June 28 (Box-folder 2: 9)
- Dossier of Information on the Rhine Valley, 1919 and undated
  - Nuestes Rhein-Panorama von Mainz bis Koeln (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Photographs and drawings of Koblenz (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Various maps depicting the Rhine River (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - Texts and drawings pertaining to railways in the Rhine Valley (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Pamphlet for the anniversary of George Washington's birthday on the Rhine in Koblenz, Germany, 1919 February 22 (Box-folder 2: 14)